[shivering]
Well, this certainly has been
a glorious day,
but I'd better get back
to class.
[mumbling]
[chuckles]
You said it, buddy.
Where do you think
you're going SquarePants?!
You just got here.
Well, I'm sorry, Sandy,
but I just got to get back
to class.
Sure you can't stay
for just a short spell,
SpongeBob?
I mean, it's such a nice day
and everyone's having
a good time.
[all]
Hi, SpongeBob!
No. I gave Mrs. Puff my word
and I shall not betray her.
Not even for a game of badminton
with me and Dale here?
Okay, maybe just one game.
I'm serving it up, SpongeBob,
ready or not!
Patrick, you remember
how to play this game?
Mm-mm.
Is this the one
with the lowest score wins?
Nice job, SpongeBob.
You're serve.
Here it comes!
[grunting]
Hey, I'm getting pretty good
at this game.
He's about to beat
the undefeated Sandy Cheeks
at her own game.
SpongeBob! SpongeBob! SpongeBob!
SpongeBob! SpongeBob!
[grunting]
Yay!
[chuckles]
Excuse me, ma'am.
[whistling
Hey, best friend,
check this out.
It's a small plastic disc
that you throw.
Small plastic disc
that you throw?!
I love playing
small plastic disc
that you throw.
I do too, buddy.
If only small plastic disc
that you throw had a shorter,
catchier name.
Oh. Oh! How about
small plastic disc
that you toss?
Perfect! Now run along, Patrick
and I'll toss it to ya!
Ready?!
[laughing]
That's why they
call it a sandwi...
[laughing]
I caught it!
Good work, man.
[gasping]
I see you've read my book.
Craig Mammalton?
The tanest man on TV?
[chuckles]
None other.
Oh,
look at those gorgeous wrinkles.
What, these?
[cheering]
Oh, and his skin,
it's so leathery.
Well, I don't mean to brag,
but, uh...
[cheering]
Whose Craig Mammalton?
You don't know
who Craig Mammalton is?
He's like so tan.
Legend has it that his tan is
so deep
that even his bones are
rich caramel brown.
Wow.
His mother must be so proud.
Please, people, please,
there'll be plenty of time
to admire my body this weekend
at my annual summer shindig.
[cheering]
Wow, Patrick, an invitation
to our first summer shindig.
And here it is.
Can I help you, little fella?
Seems to be stuck.
Yeah, I don't think
this is your type of party.
I don't want to embarrass
you guys...
Hey, everyone, check this out!
...but this party is
for the pigmentally gifted.
Must be this tan to enter.
And your skin is as light
and smooth
as, uh, well as a baby's bottom.
[laughing]
Why, thank you.
We did put on a few extra coats
of sunscreen today.
In fact...
it's time for another coat.
We've got to look our best.
Losers.
[laughing]
You're not coming to my party...
without a tan.
So, Squidward,
what you wanna talk about?
Well, it's, uh, kind of hard
to put into words.
Oh, I've been there, amigo.
You have?
Sure,
but nothing clears the sawdust
out of your brains quicker
than a ride on a jet ski.
Ever been
on one of these little babies?
Um, no, they always seemed
a little sporty for me.
Well, you only live once.
And I just happen to have
an extra helmet.
What the heck.
Hey!
[sighing]
Ow!
Ow! Hey, watch it!
[snoring]
There's blubber mouth.
There's Plankton's patty.
You know what to do.
Do I?
Oh, yeah.
[snoring]
[groaning]
[screaming]
Oh, well. No patty for Plankton.
[crying]
I'm going in.
Eh. Just being
near a whale's mouth
gives me the creeps.
[screaming]
Quiet, you fool,
you'll wake up Pearl.
[snoring]
[sighing]
Smell that fresh seawater.
Oh.
[chuckles]
Right. Sorry.
[sighing]
[yawning]
See Sandy,
nothing to worry about.
Baby sitting is easy.
[snoring]
Hey, Uncle SpongeBob.
Eh?
Open your eyes.
You're just gonna love...
our sandy surprise.
It's our gift to you.
Well, isn't that sweet.
And it won't wash away.
Cause it's made of concrete.
[mumbling]
Good structural integrity,
girls, but little tight.
So sorry, Uncle.
We made it too small.
But we'll get you out.
With this wrecking ball!
A wrecking what? Owsie.
[squawking]
[grunting]
Let's all go to my house
and take a little break.
[groaning]
On, no.
A stomach ache at the beach?
That's no fun.
I wish it would go away. Huh?
Your wish is granted.
Hold out your hand.
Wow. What is this?
For fast relief of indigestion,
try Gush and Flush
and wash your pain
down the drain.
And my stupid husband
while you're at it.
[sighing, groaning]
[arguing]
[screaming]
[groaning]
Thank you extra strength
Gush and Flush.
[chuckles]
[grunting]
Let's kick it up a notch.
[screaming]
[panting]
[groaning]
Shee-oot, SpongeBob.
How we gonna go swimming
when you're in a shirt and tie?
Oh, yes, how foolish of me.
[laughing]
Allow me to remedy
said situation right now.
I will just use
this changing tent here
to change into my bathing suit.
And I won't do anything else.
SpongeBob's acting jumpier
than a rattlesnake
in a pickle barrel.
Wait. What?
[laughing]
Oh, I'll be changing, all right,
but not into a bathing suit.
Wait until Sandy sees
that I brought my karate gear.
Hi-yah! Hi-yah!
Sandy won't beat me this time
because I've got
the elements on my side,
the elements of surprise.
Hi-yah!
[Sandy]
SpongeBob! Are you ready?
Yeah, Sandy,
I most certainly am ready.
Ready to get it on.
- Hi-i-i...
- Hi-yah!
Look, SpongeBob,
we both brought our karate gear.
[laughing]
Great minds think alike,
I suppose.
Hi-yah!
I may be down, but I'm not out.
Way to go, buddy.
It took us three days
to make that potato salad.
Three days!
Hi-yah! Sandy?
Oh, I'm Sandy, all right.
I'm very sandy. Hi-yah!
Oh, I get it.
She's Sandy.
That's her name
and she's also covered in- yes.
On your mark, get set, eat!
Wow, you two are off
like a herd of turtles.
Watch this.
[grunting]
[belching]
I win.
Hot dang!
I'm faster than green grass
through a goose.
Hmm. These jumbo dogs are
much too big
for your baby heads.
[grunting]
These dinky dogs should do ya.
Thank you.
You're welcome!
[air horn sounding]
Ee-yah!
I win again! That's right.
[groaning]
I own all of y'all. Yeehaw!
What a beautiful day.
You said it, pal.
Can you believe that sun?
I could look at it all day.
Huh? Patrick?
- What?
- Nothing.
So, how's that tan coming?
I don't know. Let me check.
Looking good.
How's yours?
Just a minute.
[screaming]
I could have sworn
I was laying on my back.
[laughing]
Yeah!
Whoo!
Larry! Larry! Larry! Larry!
Hey, it's Larry the life guard.
Mr. Lifeguard,
can I feel your muscle?
Sure. Don't scratch the paint.
Lifeguard, how's the tubage?
Gnarly, dudes.
Alright! Yeah! Whoo hoo!
Lifeguard,
can you point out the snack bar?
Right over there.
But you guys are way too old
and unsightly for my beach.
And I'm afraid I'm gonna have
to ask you to leave.
So polite.
Just like we raised him.
What a guy.
Is it any wonder
he's so popular?
Just imagine...
if I were a lifeguard.
That would be so cool.
Oh, what do you want
to be a lifeguard for?
Nobody really likes those guys.
Being a lifeguard is so dumb.
All they do is blow, blow, blow
on their stupid whistles,
rub, rub, rub that white stuff
on their noses
and show off
their gross misshapen bodies!
Dude, put that thing away.
They're, like, children here.
I'm going to the snack bar.
Who needs to be a lifeguard?
I'm cool.
I'm every bit as cool as Larry.
And if I'm not, let me be struck
by...
[thundering]
a flying ice cream truck.
And live!
Please do not land flying
ice cream trucks on the bathers!
[groaning]
SpongeBob, you okay?
Hey, I didn't know
you were a lifeguard.
Lifeguard?
The nose.
[gasping]
White stuff.
You think I'm a lifeguard?
Sure. There's no hiding
the lifeguard look, SpongeBob,
and you've got it.
You really think so?
You bet I do.
Say we're a little shorthanded
around here.
How would you like to work
the beach?
I'd love it!
Alright.
Leave that on the bench, Kahuna.
Hey, Annette, come here!
I want you to meet my buddy,
SpongeBob.
Hi.
Babe, guy's a lifeguard.
[whistling]
It works!
[music playing]
Surf's up in the Goo Lagoon.
And here comes Larry doing
his trademark lay back.
There goes Sandy hanging ten,
fingers, that is.
There goes SpongeBob...
ripping his pants again.
Hey, look, a cardboard box
washed up on the beach.
Holy fish paste! It's a guy!
Why?! Why?! Why?!!
SpongeBob.
Come closer.
I need... I need...
[gasping]
What do you need?
A tailor.
Because I ripped my pants!
[laughing]
[groaning]
That kinda stuff is
uncalled for.
What is that?
That wasn't funny, SpongeBob.
Y'all had me worried sick.
Dude.
[crying]
Plankton,
what are you doing here?
And why are you crying?
Oh, hi, SpongeBob
[blowing nose]
I'm crying because I've got
these two ice cream cones,
but I only need one.
[crying]
I don't know what to do
with the other one.
[crying]
I'll eat one
of those ice cream cones
for you.
SpongeBob,
would you do that for me?
Sure.
SpongeBob?
SpongeBob.
- SpongeBob!
- Yeah?
Isn't it great to get the things
you desire?
Like that ice cream cone,
for instance?
You can have anything you want
with a little training.
Training?
- Yes.
You just have to learn
to be more assertive,
and I can show you how.
- Assertive, huh?
- That's right.
Anything I want?
Sounds great!
Wonderful.
[laughing]
SpongeBob.
Don't let that guy sit on you.
Assertiveness lesson number one:
Tell him to get off!
Um, excuse me. Sir,
you're sitting on my body,
which is also my face.
No, no, be assertive.
Beep beep.
Not insertive!
SpongeBob,
you missed your chance.
You've got to be aggressive
to get the things you want.
You're too soft.
- But I'm a s--
- Don't say it.
There's the guy
who took your ice cream.
Don't you want it back?
Ice cream.
Listen, you, my friend's got
something to say.
What? Who said that?
Was it you?
Tell them off, SpongeBob.
Assert yourself!
That's my ice cream cone.
Great. Now let him have it!
You can have it.
Say thanks.
No! I show you how.
Hey, pencil neck.
Yeah, you. Slither over here!
Surrender that ice cream cone
or every waking moment for you
will become a swirling torrent
of pain and misery!
[crying]
Hey, that guy was crying.
Those were tears of joy.
He was happy
that you were assertive.
Yeah.
You see how wonderful life
can be... when you're maniacal?
Uh, I thought
it was called assertive.
Whatever.
Well, if it got me
this ice cream, then I like it.
Ahoy, there!
Whoa.
My name is Eugene Krabs,
and I would like to know
if I can interest
either one of you in a fresh,
delicious Krabby Patty
fresh off the grill.
Are they free?
Yes. Today they're only $3 each.
Sounds great.
But I left my wallet
up on the sand.
I told you.
- Yee-ee-ee-haw!
- What?
I love the beach.
Oh, that noise was Sandy.
Y'all be careful. Looks like
some big waves a comin'.
- Who are you?
- Hey, either you buy a patty
or get off me wave.
Cowabunga!
What next?
[babbling]
Oh.
Aloha, Patrick!
Hey, there, young feller!
How'd you like to be
our first customer
in over 17 working days?
I'd love to!
Squidward, show him a menu.
Uh, I can't quite see it
from here.
I'll just have to climb
on board.
[laughing]
That's a good one, Patrick,
on board! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Careful!
You're gonna capsize us!
Almost up.
[screaming]
You idiot!
[groaning]
Patrick, look out!
Locals only!
What'd she say?!
[screaming]
Wipe out!
Well, if you think
you can take down this castle,
my answer is bring it on!
[laughing]
[clearing throat]
Patrick, I'm trying to be
the nice guy here, okay?
Let's call
this silly business off.
No way. You started it.
Fine! Have it your way.
[laughing]
Whatever.
[gasping]
No, no, no, no.
[screaming]
[laughing]
Whoa!
Oh, hello. And goodbye.
[screaming]
Aha!
Come on!
How you like them apples?
[gasping]
[laughing]
You'll never win
and do ya hear me?!
Uh-huh. Mm hmm.
Well put, General.
We'll create
a surprise military diversion
and break through enemy lines.
What say you? Yes.
We shall ready ourselves
immediately.
How you like me now?
I like you this much.
Whoa!
Feel me!
[groaning]
Patrick?
Patrick! Are you okay?!
Question is... will you be?
[screaming]
[laughing]
There are lots of ways
to have fun here.
Dudes, bury me!
[laughing]
See what I mean?
All done.
All right!
Bubble Buddy, you dig him out
while I get some cotton candy.
Don't just stand there, dude,
the tide's coming in.
[laughing]
Dude?
My friend's in there.
Congratulations.
Whoo! Shake it! Whoo whoo!
Shake it!
Yeah, shake that bubble butt!
Yeah!
[mumbling]
Is my butt big?
Oh, oh, oh,
it's the world-famous surfer,
Grubby Grouper!
Later, groupies!
Grubby's got to go catch
some gnarly pounders.
[howling]
Oh, I'll never wash
this flipper again.
Hey, Pearl,
shake hands with Bubble Buddy.
Wha?
[crying]
It's his first time on his own.
Once again, congratulations.
Popcorn! Peanuts!
Ice cold drinks!
[whistling]
Two hours is long enough!
That's it!
Hey, Bubble Buddy,
you're finished.
He kept us waiting for a bubble?
That's nothing.
He called us fat.
[crying]
He washed my flipper.
He owes me money!
He made me provide
excellent service!
Dude, he made me
experience high tide!
Oh-h-h!
I'm telling you, he's huge.
Have you guys seen
SpongeBob anywhere?
You mean MuscleBob BuffPants?
He's in there.
Uh, whatever. Thanks.
I start off with 20 raw eggs
every day, but that's just me.
- Pardon me.
- Working out is my life.
I remember when I used to look
like that guy over there.
Who me?
[laughing]
I remember when
I used to look like you, too.
[laughing]
But that was a long time ago.
- Here's your drink, sir.
- Thank you.
[grunting]
Oops.
[slurping]
Yeah.
SpongeBob?
Wh- Where'd you get
those muscles?
I created
my own workout routine
that's giving me
amazing results.
Oops. Yeah,
I have never felt better.
- Heck, what's your secret?
- What?
Your secret work out,
what is it?
Yeah, I mean come on.
Yeah, enough.
Hmm. Well, I, uh,
first, I take my hand,
and I do this.
Are you kidding?
Do these muscles lie?
I'm glad to see you found
an exercise program
that works for you.
Yeah,
your workout routine wasn't
quite tough enough for me.
Can't argue with those results.
What you need to do now is
put those muscles to the test.
I don't know, SpongeBob,
this looks pretty dangerous.
Yeah, yeah, you said it, buddy.
Now we're really living
like Larry.
Well, will you look at that?
Now there's two guys
who know how to live.
Prepare for countdown.
I'm proud of them.
Wait a minute,
with that angle of trajectory,
they'll land right in...
Ripper's Reef.
They'll be ripped to shreds!
Wait! Don't do it! Stop!
Three, two, one, lift off.
Drat!
Whoo! Whoo hoo! Whoo whoo whoo!
Huh?
Whoa!
[grunting]
Look, guys, my advice wasn't
meant to be taken literally!
I meant to live life
to the fullest,
not to maim yourselves!
Look!
Uh-oh!
[screaming]
No!
Well, I had better be off now.
Don't go, SpongeBob,
think about your fans.
Well, if it's for the fans,
I guess I can play
just one game more.
Not today, yellow.
You're playing
with a convicted felon,
and we know he's violated
his parole somehow.
You might as well confess, Dale.
Hey, man,
I haven't done nothing.
Oh, yeah?
What have you got in there?
Hmm. Quasi gummy
chewy candy fish.
Is this how you have fun?
By eating your own kind?
Scum like you make me sick.
Cuff him.